Guide to the Department of Political Science, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Political Science, Yale University, records
1936-1983
RU 409
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
11
(22 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, proposals, personnel records, and student files documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Political Science.
Yale University. Department of Political Science
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, proposals, personnel records, and student files documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Political Science.
Political science -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Employees; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Department of Political Science
- Records, 1936-1971; Accession 1972-A-002
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Afro-American Studies at Yale, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Political Science Association, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arms Control and Disarmament Agency (ACDA): Deutsch, Russett & Merritt, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Asia Policy, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Center for Studies in Education, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Citizenship Clearing House, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Latin American Studies, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Comptroller's Office: financial material, 1954-1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conference on Responsible Leadership in a Democracy, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Core Research in Political Science, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cornell Report, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Departmental Policy on Work-loads, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Development of Political Science at Yale, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Executive Committee for the Social Sciences and History, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Future Needs of the Department of Political Science: Report of Executive Committee Reuben A. Holden, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Gilpatrick, Roswell L.: University Council, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Harold Ames Hatch Prize, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - History of Political Science Department, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Howland Memorial Prize, 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - International Relations Council: original duties, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Inter-University Case Program, Inc., 1956-1970 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Inter-University Consortium for Political Research, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Knowledge (Technologies), 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Legislative Services Program, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Library Committee, 1954-1965 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Needs and plans, 1958-1962 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Newark Advocate planning, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Office for Advanced Political Studies
    - Annual Reports, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 34 - 35)
    - Background, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Computer Instruction Program, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 38 - 43)
    - Current activities, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Establishment of Office for Advanced Political Studies, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Faculty research interests, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Faculty research: future plans, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - File contents list, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Future development, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Future programs, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 51 - 53)
    - General correspondence and memoranda, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - General statement on development of Political Science at Yale, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Grants, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Machiavelli's 500th birthday, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Memoranda, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 58 - 59)
    - Notices and announcements, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Performance systems, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Programs, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Projects, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Prospectus, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Restructuring, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Seminar on the Future, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 66 - 69)
    - Seminar on the Future, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 70 - 74)
  - Office of Economic Opportunity: correspondence memoranda, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Peace Corps: Extracts from a Guide to Training Program, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - "Political Behavior as a Field of Political Science", undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Political Science Research Library
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1962-1969 (Box 6, Folder 78 - 79)
    - Future of Political Science Research Library, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Newsletters, guides, reports, 1963-1968 (Box 7, Folder 81 - 82)
    - Reports and budgets, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 83 - 84)
  - Political Union, "Politics House": James Rhea and Allen Barrington, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Position descriptions, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Provost: Norman S. Buck, 1934-1961 (Box 7, Folder 87 - 88)
  - Report of Graduate Curriculum, 1958-1963 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Report of the President's Committee on General Education, 1958-1963 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - S-19843: "Full opportunity and Social Accounting Act of 1967" and related material (Box 8, Folder 91 - 92)
  - Secretary: Reuben A. Holden, 1953-1965 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Russian and European Studies, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - The Robert A. Taft Institute of Government Urban Affairs, 1954-1967 (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - Affairs: Sumaries of faculty research, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 97)
    - Data, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 98 - 99)
    - Meeting comments, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 100)
    - Planning Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 101)
    - Studies: correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - Studies: program, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 103 - 104)
  - Wilbur Cross Medal, 1966-1968 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Yale College Dean: before 1969, 1951-1969 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Yale Political Science Series, 1952-1962 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Yale University Council, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Advanced Research Projects Agency (ARPA), 1967 (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - Biology and Politics, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Census Use Study, 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Center on International Problems, 1968, undated (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Committee on the Department of Teaching and Research in Political Science at Yale, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 114)
  - Comparative Administration Group and F. W. Fesler, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Comparative Sociology, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - "A Comparative Study of the National and International Processes of Collection Decision-Making", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 117)
  - Computer Proposal, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Department Proposals, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 119 - 120)
  - Forestry, School of, 1966-1968 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Health Services, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - Law and Behavioral Science: Russell Sage project, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 124)
  - Math and Politics, 1958-1968 (Box 12, Folder 125 - 126)
  - National Institute of Mental Health, 1966-1969 (Box 12, Folder 127)
  - National Science Foundation
    - Application for Summer Program, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 128)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 129)
    - Department Development Grant, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 130)
    - Department Development Plans, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 131)
    - Financial material, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 132 - 134)
    - Graduate traineeship, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 135)
    - Progress Report, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 136)
      - Progress Report on summer applicants for final report, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 137)
    - Proposal on Alliances, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 138)
    - Prospectuses, Reports: Summer research, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 139)
    - Renewal for summer, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 140)
    - Rule books, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 141)
    - Statistical Service, 1966-1968 (Box 14, Folder 142)
    - Summer grant: general, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 143)
    - Undergraduate research participation, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 144 - 146)
    - Undergraduate research projects, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 147)
  - Normative Theory Projects: National Endowment for the Humanities, 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 148)
  - Office for Advanced Political Studies
    - Asian, South East Program, 1968, undated (Box 14, Folder 149)
    - Compensation Administration, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 152)
    - Grant proposals: miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 153)
    - Office for Social Science Research, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 154)
    - Psychology and Science, 1967-1968, undated (Box 15, Folder 155)
    - Public Affairs Center at Yale, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 156)
    - Research on International Alliances and Alignments, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 157)
    - Research and Education in International Politics, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 158)
    - Yale Atlantic Community, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 159)
    - Yale International Organization Work-Study Program (draft), undated (Box 15, Folder 160)
  - Political Socialization, 1967, undated (Box 15, Folder 161)
  - Program in Social Ethics, 1968, undated (Box 15, Folder 162)
  - Program of Graduate Training in Public Administration, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 163)
  - Program of Teaching and Research in International Relations, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 164)
  - Program on Technology and Society: E. G. Mesthene, Harvard, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 165)
  - Proposal for Establishing a Program in European and North Atlantic Area Studies, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 166)
  - Proposal for a Program in Training in Political Theory, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 167)
  - Proposal for Research and Training in Area Studies, International Relations and Foreign Policy, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 168)
  - Undergraduate Introduction Courses in Political Investigating and Method Analysis, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 170)
  - Undergraduate Introduction Courses in Political Thinking, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 171)
  - Work-Study Programs, 1968-1970 (Box 16, Folder 172)
  - The Yale Atlantic Community of Scholars, 1967-1968, undated (Box 16, Folder 173)
  - Yale International Political Data Program, 1962-1969 (Box 16, Folder 174 - 176)
  - Yale Political Science Series, 1963-1968 (Box 16, Folder 177)
  - American Political Science Association, 1955-1960 (Box 17, Folder 178)
  - Chubb Fellowship Fund, 1940-1947 (Box 17, Folder 179 - 180)
  - Dean's Office: Graduate School, 1951-1969 (Box 17, Folder 181 - 183)
  - Fellowships: Colleges, 1959-1963 (Box 17, Folder 185)
  - National Science Foundation
    - Application for Undergraduate Research Participation: Summer Field Research Funds, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 186)
    - Student applications, letters of recommendation, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - Office of Advanced Political Studies
    - Business manager candidate, 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 189)
    - Personnel, 1967-1969 (Box 18, Folder 190)
  - Post-doctoral files, 1962-1969 (Box 18, Folder 191 - 192)
  - Post-doctoral inquiries and Fellows appointed, 1962-1969 (Box 18, Folder 193)
  - Urban Department, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 194)
- Correspondence of Joseph LaPalombara as chairman, 1975; Accession 19ND-A-374
  - Correspondence of Joseph LaPalombara as chairman, 1975 (Box 1)
- Faculty personnel records, 1944-1983; Accession 2000-A-052
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2059
  - Faculty (Ladder-track) Personnel files
    - A-G
    - H-Pa
    - Pr-Y